Guide to the Dorothy Norman Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- April 1997 Acquisition, 1908-1996; 4; 54.38; 55 boxes
  - Personal and Professional Papers
    - [From box labelled, "Indira, India notes, 'Encounters' ms. 12/90"-- Folder "Gandhi's Assassination" was taken from this file]
      - Newspaper article, October 4-11, 1985; TIME magazine, issue November 12, 1984; Newspaper article, September 13, 1985; Miscellaneous news articles, writings, invitations, correspondence, page proofs for "Indira Gandhi: Letters to an American Friend", essay on "India", 1952-1985, undated (Box 162)
      - Misc. articles, writings, manuscript materials re: Indira Gandhi, 1965-1985 (Box 162)
      - "Memoir: HW (?) copy; Fldr 1, pp 1-122; corr as of 8/80": "'Memoir' by Dorothy Norman", undated (Box 162)
      - "Indira": miscellaneous writings, ms.-related, personal correspondence, invitations, 1941-1965, undated (Box 162)
      - Misc. correspondence, misc. writings including ms. corrections to Dorothy Mandel's book on Alfred Stieglitz & a translated draft of the Bhagavad Gita, 1970-1986, undated (Box 162)
      - Misc. news articles & copy of Karim H. Sednaoui, "Thesis: Alexey Brodovitch, His Work, His Influence" c. 1974. Mis- labelled "Photography - 1974-75", 1962-1975 (Box 162)
      - The Archive, Issue No. 22, Jan 1986 with "The Letters from Tina Modotti to Edward Weston", 1986 January (Box 163)
      - "Books Corresp. & orders 1973 - (old folder in next room), news clippings, 1972-1976 (Box 163)
      - "Clippings," folder with miscellaneous news articles, 1978-1995? (Box 163)
    - "Early Spring and Autumn Moon: 1993 Engagement Calendar" Art Institute of Chicago (Box 163)
    - "For DN/AS, An American Place Gallery: Early Lists", 1903-1932 (Box 163)
    - "Items from Stieglitz's collection" & "Catalogue of the Alfred Stieglitz Collection for Fisk University", 1937, 1949 (Box 163)
    - "Metropolitan Museum Lists," business correspondence & related materials, 1933-1972, undated (Box 163)
    - MOMA: Five Membership Guest Admissions & "Ledger," a bound book with lists, names, miscellaneous information regarding "An American Place", 1932, undated (Box 163)
    - "Printing (companies, pamphlets, price lists, etc.)", 1951-1960, undated (Box 163)
    - "Philadelphia Museum of Art exhibition of DN collection; copyrights for catalogue illustrations", undated (Box 163)
    - Unsorted photographs, undated (Box 163)
    - Illustrations from The Hero, undated; 4 (Box 164)
    - Bound journal. "April 1929 - Feb 1930; "Finished 1947," 300 pp.; 2 bound books: 1 entitled, "Stories" by Alfred Stieglitz (w/ a listing of Stieglitz's works) & "'Book II'--February-June 1930" (continuation of DN's journal); Bound book, "The Baby's Biography" by A. O. Kaplan [Edward A. Norman's baby book], 1930-1947; 3 (Box 165)
    - Tape recorder (Sony BM-12) in original box, undated (Box 166)
      Sound recording equipment: Use of originals is restricted. Consult Access Services for further information.
    - Untitled, undated; 1; 00:04:04; A high amount of background noise can be heard on the tape. The program is distorted at times. The speed of the audio ramps up near the end of the program. (Box 166, Item barcode 39002091243288)
      Audiovisual material. Restricted fragile. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
  - Scrapbooks, Series V
    - Clippings "1931-1941" and "Stieglitz handwriting samples" (folder of envelopes and notes); "Reaching Out" (brochure), 1931-1941, undated (Box 167 (Oversize))
    - Clippings "1942-1944" (Box 168 (Oversize))
    - Clippings "April 1944 to January 1946", 1944-1946 (Box 169 (Oversize))
    - Clippings "January 1946 to June 1948", 1946-1948 (Box 170 (Oversize))
    - Clippings "July 1948 to December 1953", 1948-1953 (Box 171 (Oversize))
    - Clippings "September 1953 to December 1956", 1953-1956 (Box 172 (Oversize))
    - Clippings "1957-1961" (Box 173 (Oversize))
    - Clippings "1962-1967" (Box 174 (Oversize))
    - Clippings "1968 to 1973", 1968-1973 (Box 175 (Oversize))
    - Clippings "1973-1979" (Box 176 (Oversize))
    - Clippings "1980 to Present" (Box 177 (Oversize))
    - Clippings 1946-1953, 1980-1981, 1946-1981 (Box 178 (Oversize))
    - "Nehru: The First Sixty Years, 1965'" (Box 179 (Oversize))
    - "Her Encounter, 1958" (Box 180 (Oversize))
    - "The Hero, 1969" (Box 181 (Oversize))